fernanda mora

B.Sc. Applied Mathematics

■ B.Sc. Actuarial Sciences

■ M.Sc. Computer Science candidate



about Mexico city

a.cotton.soul@gmail.com

github.com/Sophie-Germain

languages spanish (native) english (high proficiency)

programming

R, Python, Matlab (fair) Java, C, Bash (basic)

other

PostgreSQL, LaTeX, Sublime, Office Suite, GitHub, Docker

interests

"If you cannot measure it, you cannot improve it". My major goal is to **generate value** through *state-of-the-art technologies and models* that tackle relevant problems in *society, government and companies*. My second goal is to promote a quantitative & data-driven approach to problem-solving and decision-making.

To achieve this I have developed a unique academic & industry experience that combines theory + research with a practical + client-oriented approach.

Academic interests

- Computer Science: computer architecture, distributed computing, Android OS security
- · Machine Learning: Deep Learning
- Data Science: Big Data, Cloud computing
- Pure Mathematics: Set Theory, Functional Analysis, Group Theory
- Statistics and Finance: Bayesian, Derivatives, Risk Theory

Non-academic interests

- Strategic and Management Consulting
- · Value proposition and pricing
- Business intelligence analytics with data-driven solutions
- Integration, management, securing, and analysis of enterprise and governmental data
- Startups
- · Web Development

education

2016 2m

since 2015	M.Sc. candidate in Computer Science Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico <i>Working on machine reading comprehension</i>
2015	B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Thesis with special mention: Deep Learning fundamentals with an application
	to forecast electric energy demand in Mexico. Link to thesis Link to deck
2012	B.Sc. in Actuarial Sciences Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo de Mexico Link to thesis

academic experience

Carnagia Mallon University

2010, 2111	Carriegie Melion University		Isiting Research Scholar	
	Worked with Profr. Eric Nyberg in Machine learning models for Q&A at the			
	Language Technologies Institute.	Link to project report		
2016	Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo Teaching Data Mining tools to supp		luate Seminar Professor Github repo	
2015, 6m	Computational Research and An Machine learning and visualization	,	,	
2010, 6m	Instituto Tecnológico Autónomo Economics IV (non-competitive ma		Teaching Assistant	

industry experience

since 2015	Freelance consulting Business strategy, data mining and statistical consulting	Consultant
2015, 2m	AbbVie Mexico Tailor-made value propositions for AbbVie's drug portfolio	Project Coordinator
2013-2014	LifeSciences Consultants <i>Health economics, cost-effectiveness analysis, market access</i>	agement Consultant
2010-2011	Sociedad Financiera Campesina Evaluation and assessment of credit portfolios	Financial Analyst
2012, 3m	ADRISA Estimation and forecasting of the premium of life insurances	Actuarial Analyst
2009-2010	Cuasar Capital S.C. Financial assessment of infrastructure and real-state projects	Financial Analyst

publications

Local layered algorithmic model for topological design of rural telecommunications networks. Presented on the International Conference on Operations Research for Development, ICORD 2016. Link to paper

Carga Económica de la Diabetes Mellitus en México, 2013. Fundación Mexicana para la Salud A.C. Link to paper

conferences

International Conference on Operations Research for Development, ICORD 2016: Presenter of a paper and revisor of two papers.

acknowledgments

- 90% Bachelor's tuition scholarship for strong academic performance
- 60% Master's tuition scholarship for strong academic performance
- National Council of Science and Technology Master's scholarship for strong academic performance

skills & competencies

- Unique academic-industry profile that combines theory and research with practice and client experience
- Solid mathematical modeling, research, analysis and problem solving techniques
- Multidisciplinary knowledge of relevant areas such as data science, computer science, statistics, probability, finance and economics
- Creative, entrepreneurial, efficient, a quick-learner, enthusiastic about intellectual challenges, trust-worthy, a team player and hard-working